A Guide to the Records of Lieutenant Governor Timothy M. Kaine, 1995-2005 (bulk 2002-2005)
Library of Virginia
- Series II: Constituent Correspondence, 2002-2005., Extent: 53 boxes. (Box 17-72)
  - Subseries A: Chronological Files, 2002-2005., 26 boxes.
    - 2004
      - Ma (Box 34, Folder 6)
      - Mc-Mi (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - Mo-My (Box 35, Folder 2)
      - N (Box 35, Folder 3)
      - O (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - P (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - Ra-Ri (Box 35, Folder 6)
      - Ro-Ry (Box 35, Folder 7)
      - Sa-Se (Box 36, Folder 1)
      - Sh-Sn (Box 36, Folder 2)
      - So-Sy (Box 36, Folder 3)
      - T (Box 36, Folder 4)
      - U-V (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - Wa-Wh (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - Wi (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Wi-Wy (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - Y (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - Z (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - Do Not Respond Letters
        - B-K (Box 37, Folder 5)
        - H-Q (Box 37, Folder 6)
        - R-Z (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - 2005
      - Aa-Ap (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Ar-Ay (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - Bai-Bap (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Bar-Bat (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - Be-Bl (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - Bo-Brough (Box 38, Folder 6)
      - Brow-Bu (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Ca-Cl (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Coa-Cos (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - Cou-Cy (Box 39, Folder 4)
      - Da-De (Box 39, Folder 5)
      - Di-Dun (Box 39, Folder 6)
      - Dup-Dur (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - E (Box 40, Folder 2)
      - F (Box 40, Folder 3)
      - Ga-Gl (Box 40, Folder 4)
      - Go-Gu (Box 40, Folder 5)
      - Hac-Har (Box 40, Folder 6)
      - Har-He (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Hi-Hy (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Harlow, Larry (Box 41, Folder 3)
      - I (Box 41, Folder 4)
      - J (Box 41, Folder 5)
      - K (Box 41, Folder 6)
      - La-Li (Box 41, Folder 7)
      - Lo-Ly (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Ma (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Mc-Mi (Box 42, Folder 3)
      - Ml-Mu (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - N (Box 42, Folder 5)
      - O (Box 42, Folder 6)
      - Pa (Box 42, Folder 7)
      - Pe-Pu (Box 43, Folder 1)
      - Q (Box 43, Folder 2)
      - Ra-Ri (Box 43, Folder 3)
      - Ro-Ru (Box 43, Folder 4)
      - Sa-Sci (Box 43, Folder 5)
      - Sco-Sh (Box 43, Folder 6)
      - Si-So (Box 43, Folder 7)
      - Sp-Sw (Box 44, Folder 1)
      - T (Box 44, Folder 2)
      - U (Box 44, Folder 3)
      - V (Box 44, Folder 4)
      - Wa (Box 44, Folder 5)
      - We-Wh (Box 44, Folder 6)
      - Wi-Wy (Box 44, Folder 7)
      - Y (Box 44, Folder 8)
      - Primary Interstate Waste Bill
        - A-C (Box 45, Folder 1)
        - D-G (Box 45, Folder 2)
        - H-L (Box 45, Folder 3)
        - M-P (Box 45, Folder 4)
        - R-Z (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Subseries B: Subject Files, 2002-2005., 27 boxes.
    This subseries is housed in twenty-seven archival boxes and is arranged in alphabetical order by subject. The subseries contains correspondence, invitations, reports, publications, press releases, news clippings, event briefings, photographs, legislation, and other background material maintained by the Lieutenant Governor's Office. Included are materials related to the following subjects: Economic Development, Education, General Files, Healthcare, & Invitations. The largest group within this subseries is related to invitations. The invitations are arranged chronologically by the date of the event or correspondence and often include Tim Kaine's letter in response to the invitation. In addition, there are e-mails from Sherrie Harrington, Director of Administration & Scheduling, Carey Friedman, Director of Policy, and Anita A. Rimler, Secretary of the Commonwealth. Note that invitations for 2004 are divided into confirmed invitations & regrets. There are only regrets for 2005. The General Files contain publications, correspondence, press releases, news clippings, legislation, and other items related to the budget, childcare, the Coalition for Virginia's Future, the environment, Oceana Naval Air Station, and other subjects. Also noteworthy are files related to Virginia Indian tribes and the Walter Plecker legacy.
    - Economic Development
      - Economic Assumptions for the United States & Virginia, 2004 (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Small Business, 2004 (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Small, Women, & Minority-Owned Business (SWAM), 2004 (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Virginia Economic Development Partnership Annual Report, 2003 (Box 46, Folder 4)
      - Virginia Economic Indicators, 2003 (Box 46, Folder 5)
      - Virginia Economic Trends, 2004-2005 (Box 46, Folder 6)
      - Workforce Development, 2003 (Box 46, Folder 7)
      - Workforce Training, 2003-2004 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Education
      - 2002-2003 (Box 46, Folder 9)
      - 2004 (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Accountability Committee, 2001-2002 (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Affirmative Action, 2003 (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - America's Kids Connect, 2002 (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Board of Education, 2002-2003 (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - Composite Index Summary for Elementary & Secondary School Funding, 2002-2003 (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - Council of Independent Colleges in Virginia, 2004 (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - Data Enrollment Averages, undated (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - Endowed Chairs, 2004 (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - Every Child Matters Education Fund, 2003 (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - Free & Reduced Price Lunch Program Eligibility Reports, 2000-2002 (Box 47, Folder 11)
      - Governor's Schools, 2002-2004 (Box 47, Folder 12)
      - Higher Education
        - Chartered University Initiative, 2004 (Box 47, Folder 13)
        - Scholarships, 2004-2005 (Box 48, Folder 2)
        - State Council for Higher Education in Virginia, 2002 (Box 48, Folder 3)
        - Summit
          - 2002 (Box 48, Folder 4)
          - 2003 (Box 48, Folder 4)
          - Steering Committee Meeting, 2002 (Box 48, Folder 5)
        - Tuition, 2002 (Box 48, Folder 6)
      - Highland County Public Schools, 2002 (Box 48, Folder 7)
      - Home Education, 2002 (Box 48, Folder 8)
      - K-12 Education, 2002-2005 (Box 48, Folder 9)
      - Legislative Services, 2001-2003 (Box 48, Folder 10)
      - No Child Left Behind, 2003 (Box 48, Folder 11)
      - Partnership for Achieving Successful Schools (PASS), 2003 (Box 48, Folder 12)
      - Pre-K, 2003-2004 (Box 48, Folder 13)
      - Regional Alternative Education Programs, 2003-2004 (Box 48, Folder 14)
      - Saint Gertrude High School, 2003-2004 (Box 48, Folder 15)
      - School Visits, 2001-2002 (Box 48, Folder 16)
      - Standards of Learning (SOLs), 2000-2002 (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Substitute Teachers, 2002 (Box 49, Folder 2)
      - Superintendent's Association, 2002 (Box 49, Folder 3)
      - Virginia Community College System, undated (Box 49, Folder 4)
      - Virginia Council for International Education, 2002 (Box 49, Folder 5)
      - Virginia Council for Private Education, 2002 (Box 49, Folder 6)
      - Virginia Education Coalition, 2002 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - General Files
      - Bar Associations, 2002-2003 (Box 49, Folder 8)
      - Budget
        - 2003-2004 (Box 49, Folder 9)
        - 2004 (Box 49, Folder 10)
      - Child Care
        - Adoption 2004 (Box 49, Folder 11)
        - Affordable Daycare, 2004 (Box 49, Folder 12)
        - Child Abuse, 2002-2005 (Box 49, Folder 13)
        - Early Childhood Development, 2004-2005 (Box 49, Folder 14)
        - Fatherhood, 2003 (Box 49, Folder 15)
        - Smart Start, 2003 (Box 49, Folder 16)
      - Child Pornography, 2002 (Box 50, Folder 1)
      - Child Support Enforcement, 2002-2003 (Box 50, Folder 2)
      - Coalfields Expressway, 2004 (Box 50, Folder 3)
      - Coalition for Virginia's Future
        - 2002 (Part 1) (Box 50, Folder 4)
        - 2002 (Part 2) (Box 50, Folder 5)
      - College Credit Debt, 2004 (Box 50, Folder 6)
      - Confederate History Month, 2002-2004 (Box 50, Folder 7)
      - Constituent Phone Calls, 2002-2003 (Box 50, Folder 8)
      - Death Penalty Language, 2004 (Box 50, Folder 9)
      - Death Penalty Statistics, undated (Box 50, Folder 10)
      - Disability Commission Work Group Meeting, 2003 (Box 50, Folder 11)
      - Drinking Water, 2001 (Box 50, Folder 12)
      - Dulles Corridor Rail Association, 2002 (Box 50, Folder 13)
      - Emergency Contraception Research, 2002-2005 (Box 50, Folder 13)
      - Environment
        - Miscellaneous, 2003-2005 (Box 50, Folder 14)
        - Publications, 1998-2001 (Box 51, Folder 1)
        - Solid Waste, 2003-2005 (Box 51, Folder 2)
        - Virginia Clean Streams Law, 2004 (Box 51, Folder 3)
      - Fairfax County Council of PTA's Handbook, 2005 (Box 51, Folder 4)
      - Faith & Politics
        - Articles, 2003-2004 (Box 51, Folder 3)
        - Marriage Builders Alliance of Richmond, 2004 (Box 51, Folder 4)
      - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA), 2002 (Box 51, Folder 5)
      - Gay/Lesbian Issues, 2004 (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - General Assembly Session, 2003 (Box 51, Folder 7)
      - Government Reform - Council of Virginia's Future, 2004 (Box 51, Folder 8)
      - Hispanics, 2003 (Box 51, Folder 9)
      - Interesting Ideas, 2004 (Box 51, Folder 10)
      - Jamestown 2007, 2004 (Box 51, Folder 11)
      - Legislative Agenda, 2004 (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - May, Diana, 2004 (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Media, 2002-2003 (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - Mercury Pollution, 2005 (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - National Forest Protection, 2002 (Box 52, Folder 5)
      - O'Brien, Mi-Joong, 2002 (Box 52, Folder 6)
      - Oceana Naval Air Station
        - 2004-2005 (Box 52, Folder 7)
        - 2005 (Box 52, Folder 8)
      - Pre-Marriage Counseling, 2002-2003 (Box 52, Folder 9)
      - PBS Deliberation Day Debate, 2004 (Box 52, Folder 10)
      - Public Defense Attorneys, 2004 (Box 52, Folder 11)
      - Public-Private Transportation Act Proposal for the Western Extension of the Powhite Parkway, 2003 (Box 52, Folder 12)
      - Research, 2002 (Box 52, Folder 13)
      - Resumes, 2003 (Box 52, Folder 14)
      - Richmond to Washington Rail, 2004 (Box 52, Folder 15)
      - Rural Economic Development, 2002 (Box 52, Folder 16)
      - Secure Virginia, 2002-2003 (Box 52, Folder 17)
      - Spanish Web Site, Undated (Box 52, Folder 18)
      - Speech Ideas, 2003-2004 (Box 52, Folder 19)
      - Standardized Testing, 2003 (Box 52, Folder 20)
      - Threats, 2003 (Box 52, Folder 21)
      - Transportation, 2004 (Box 52, Folder 22)
      - Unfinished Constituent Business, 2003-2004 (Box 53, Folder 1)
      - Unfinished Press Releases, 2003-2004 (Box 53, Folder 2)
      - Virginia Birth Injury Program, 2001-2002 (Box 53, Folder 3)
      - Virginia Department of Transportation, 2000-2002 (Box 53, Folder 4)
      - Virginia Farm Bureau Teleconference, 2004 (Box 53, Folder 5)
      - Virginia Indian Tribes & Walter Plecker Legacy, 2002-2004 (Box 53, Folder 6)
      - Virginia Military Institute Supper Prayer, 2004 (Box 53, Folder 7)
      - Virginia State Bar, 2003 (Box 53, Folder 8)
      - Virginia Wiretap Statutes, 2002 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Healthcare
      - About Coverage: Health Insurance in the United States, 2004 (Box 53, Folder 10)
      - Affordability Crisis in U.S. Healthcare, 2004 (Box 53, Folder 11)
      - Articles
        - 2000-2004 (Box 53, Folder 12)
        - 2004 (Box 53, Folder 13)
        - 2004 (Box 53, Folder 14)
        - undated (Box 53, Folder 15)
      - Basics of HSAs, 2004 (Box 54, Folder 1)
      - Building a New Health Care System, 2004 (Box 54, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence, 2004 (Box 54, Folder 3)
      - Cost Versus Value - Choice Versus Change: Small Business Owners Consider the Future of Health Care, undated (Box 54, Folder 4)
      - Department of Health Professions Biennial Report, 2003-2004 (Box 54, Folder 5)
      - Financial Impact of Mandated Health Insurance Benefits & Providers, 2003 (Box 54, Folder 6)
      - Guide to Health Insurance Options for Small Businesses in Northern Virginia, 2003 (Box 54, Folder 7)
      - Health Insurance Demonstration Project, 2004 (Box 54, Folder 8)
      - Healthcare Commission, 2004 (Box 54, Folder 9)
      - Healthcare for All of U.S.?, undated (Box 54, Folder 10)
      - Joint Commission on Health Care, 2004 (Box 54, Folder 11)
      - Legislation, 2004 (Box 54, Folder 12)
      - Lieutenant Governor's Commission on Small Business Health Care Cost, 2004 (Box 54, Folder 13)
      - Maine's State Healthcare Plan, 2004 (Box 54, Folder 14)
      - Making Healthcare Affordable to All Americans, 2004 (Box 54, Folder 15)
      - Making Medicaid a Block Grant Program, 2005 (Box 54, Folder 16)
      - Mandated Insurance Benefits Termination (HB 935), 2004 (Box 54, Folder 17)
      - Meetings, 2002-2004 (Box 55, Folder 1)
      - Memos, 2004 (Box 55, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous, 2004 (Box 55, Folder 3)
      - Monitoring the Uninsured: A State Policy Perspective, 2004 (Box 55, Folder 4)
      - One Solution to Reducing Healthcare Costs, 2004 (Box 55, Folder 5)
      - Proposal for a Virginia Community-based Coverage Initiative, 2004 (Box 55, Folder 6)
      - Protean Plan, 2004 (Box 55, Folder 7)
      - Publications, 2002-2004 (Box 55, Folder 8)
      - Report of the Governor's Work Group on Rural Obstetrical Care, 2004 (Box 55, Folder 9)
      - Report of the Joint Commission on Health Care, 2000 (Box 55, Folder 10)
      - Report of the Special Advisory Commission on Health Insurance Benefits, 2004 (Box 55, Folder 11)
      - Report of the State Corporation Commission on the Financial Impact of Mandated Health Insurance Benefits and Providers, 2004 (Box 55, Folder 12)
      - Review of Health Insurance Purchasing Cooperatives(HICPs), 1999 (Box 55, Folder 13)
      - Richmond Enhancing Access to Community Healthcare(REACH), 2003-2004 (Box 55, Folder 14)
      - Select Committee on Affordable Health Care for Floridians
        - Pages 1-160, 2002 (Box 56, Folder 1)
        - Pages 161-238, 2002 (Box 56, Folder 2)
      - Small Business Health Insurance Costs, 2004 (Box 56, Folder 3)
      - Small But Significant Steps to Help the Uninsured, 2003 (Box 56, Folder 4)
      - State Options for Expanding Health Care, 2004 (Box 56, Folder 5)
      - State Planning Grant Leadership Committee Meeting, 2004 (Box 56, Folder 6)
      - Statement of the U.S. Chamber of Commerce on America's Uninsured, 2004 (Box 56, Folder 7)
      - Study of Mandated Health Insurance Services: A Comparative Evaluation, 2004 (Box 56, Folder 8)
      - Subsidies and Financial Assistance, undated (Box 56, Folder 9)
      - Virginia Birth-Related Neurological Injury Compensation Annual Report, 2004 (Box 56, Folder 10)
      - Virginia Health Care Foundation Annual Report, 2004 (Box 56, Folder 11)
      - Virginia Health Care Insurance & Access Survey, 2005 (Box 56, Folder 12)
      - Virginia Public-Private Sector Coverage Initiative, 2002 (Box 56, Folder 13)
      - Worksite Wellness: One Solution to Reducing Healthcare Costs, 2004 (Box 56, Folder 14)
    - Invitations
      - 2002
        - January-February (Box 57, Folder 1)
        - March
          - 1-19 (Box 57, Folder 2)
          - 20-29 (Box 57, Folder 3)
        - April
          - 2-15 (Box 57, Folder 4)
          - 16-24 (Box 57, Folder 5)
          - 25-30 (Box 57, Folder 6)
        - May
          - 1-8 (Box 58, Folder 1)
          - 9-10 (Box 58, Folder 2)
          - 11-17 (Box 58, Folder 3)
          - 18-28 (Box 58, Folder 4)
          - 29-31 (Box 58, Folder 5)
        - June
          - 1-10 (Box 58, Folder 6)
          - 11-19 (Box 59, Folder 1)
          - 20-30 (Box 59, Folder 2)
        - July
          - 1-11 (Box 59, Folder 3)
          - 12-17 (Box 59, Folder 4)
          - 18-31 (Box 59, Folder 5)
        - August
          - 1-12 (Box 59, Folder 6)
          - 13-26 (Box 60, Folder 1)
          - 27-30 (Box 60, Folder 2)
        - September
          - 3-9 (Box 60, Folder 3)
          - 10-17 (Box 60, Folder 4)
          - 18-23 (Box 60, Folder 5)
          - 24-30 (Box 60, Folder 6)
        - October
          - 1-5 (Box 61, Folder 1)
          - 7-15 (Box 61, Folder 2)
          - 16-21 (Box 61, Folder 3)
          - 22-31 (Box 61, Folder 4)
        - November
          - 1-10 (Box 61, Folder 5)
          - 11-25 (Box 62, Folder 1)
          - 26-30 (Box 62, Folder 2)
        - December
          - 2-11 (Box 62, Folder 3)
          - 14-30 (Box 62, Folder 4)
      - 2003
        - January
          - 2-15 (Box 62, Folder 5)
          - 14-31 (Box 62, Folder 6)
        - February (Box 62, Folder 7)
        - March (Box 63, Folder 1)
        - April (Box 63, Folder 2)
        - May (Box 63, Folder 3)
        - June (Box 63, Folder 4)
        - July (Box 63, Folder 5)
        - August (Box 63, Folder 6)
        - September (Box 63, Folder 7)
        - October (Box 64, Folder 1)
        - November (Box 64, Folder 2)
      - 2004
        - Confirmed
          - January
            - 7-20 (Box 64, Folder 3)
            - 21-29 (Box 64, Folder 4)
          - February
            - 2-13 (Box 64, Folder 5)
            - 14-29 (Box 64, Folder 6)
          - March (Box 64, Folder 7)
          - April
            - 1-22 (Box 64, Folder 8)
            - 24-30 (Box 65, Folder 1)
          - May
            - 1-10 (Box 65, Folder 2)
            - 13-27 (Box 65, Folder 3)
          - June (Box 65, Folder 4)
          - July
            - 3-15 (Box 65, Folder 5)
            - 16-31 (Box 65, Folder 6)
          - August (Box 65, Folder 7)
          - September
            - 4-15 (Box 66, Folder 1)
            - 16-30 (Box 66, Folder 2)
          - October
            - 1-24 (Box 66, Folder 3)
            - 25-29 (Box 66, Folder 4)
          - November (Box 66, Folder 5)
          - December (Box 66, Folder 6)
        - Regrets
          - January
            - 5-23 (Box 67, Folder 1)
            - 24-31 (Box 67, Folder 2)
          - February
            - 2-21 (Box 67, Folder 3)
            - 22-28 (Box 67, Folder 4)
          - March
            - 1-16 (Box 67, Folder 5)
            - 17-31 (Box 67, Folder 6)
          - April
            - 1-15 (Box 68, Folder 1)
            - 16-22 (Box 68, Folder 2)
            - 23-30 (Box 68, Folder 3)
          - May
            - 1-10 (Box 68, Folder 4)
            - 11-18 (Box 68, Folder 5)
            - 19-31 (Box 68, Folder 6)
          - June
            - 1-12 (Box 69, Folder 1)
            - 13-21 (Box 69, Folder 2)
            - 24-30 (Box 69, Folder 3)
          - July
            - 1-16 (Box 69, Folder 4)
            - 17-31 (Box 69, Folder 5)
          - August (Box 69, Folder 6)
          - September
            - 1-12 (Box 69, Folder 7)
            - 13-21 (Box 70, Folder 1)
            - 22-27 (Box 70, Folder 2)
            - 28-30 (Box 70, Folder 3)
          - October
            - 1-7 (Box 70, Folder 4)
            - 8-15 (Box 70, Folder 5)
            - 16-22 (Box 70, Folder 6)
            - 23-31 (Box 71, Folder 1)
          - November
            - 1-11 (Box 71, Folder 2)
            - 12-17 (Box 71, Folder 3)
            - 18-30 (Box 71, Folder 4)
          - December
            - 1-9 (Box 71, Folder 5)
            - 10-28 (Box 72, Folder 1)
      - 2005
        - Regrets (Box 72, Folder 2)
- Series III. Legislation Files & Supporting Documentation, 1992-2005 (bulk 2002-2005)., Extent: 28 boxes. (Box 72-100)
  The Legislation Files and Supporting Documentation series is housed in twenty-nine archival boxes and is arranged in three subseries. Subseries have been designated for Calendar Notes (2002 Session), Legislative Issues (2002 Session), & General Files. This series documents the legislative efforts of the Office of the Lieutenant Governor with specific subseries devoted to the 2002 Session of the General Assembly.
  - Subseries A: Calendar Notes (2002 Session), 2002., 2 boxes.
    The Calendar Notes subseries is housed in two archival boxes and is arranged in alphabetical order. This subseries contains notes and legislative calendars of the Virginia Senate. The legislative calendars contain the name of the bill, the name of the patron, the committee reported from, yeas, nays, abstentions, and amendments proposed. Noteworthy is the "End of Session" file which contains reports from the Virginia Baseball Authority.
    - Jan. 14-25 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Jan. 28-31 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Feb. 1-14 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Feb. 15-28 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Mar. 1-9 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Appropriations, 2002 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Budget, 2002 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Cabinet Meetings, 2002 (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Callahan Bond Amendments, 2002 (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Clippings, 2002 (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - End of Session, 2000-2002 (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Full Cabinet Meeting, 2002 (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Kilgore, Jerry W., 2002 (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - Legislation
      - 2002 (Box 73, Folder 9)
      - 2002 (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - Referendum Bills, 2002 (Box 73, Folder 11)
    - Regional Caucuses, 2002 (Box 73, Folder 12)
    - Talking Points, 2002 (Box 73, Folder 13)
    - Warner, Mark R., 2002 (Box 73, Folder 14)
  - Subseries B: Legislative Issues (2002 Session), 2000-2004., 2 boxes.
    The Legislative Issues subseries is housed in two archival boxes and is arranged in alphabetical order. This subseries contains background information on legislative issues for the 2002 Session of the General Assembly. The subseries includes correspondence, bills, reports, notes, articles, publications, and other sundry documents. The bulk of the subseries relates to education. Additionally, there are files related to terrorism, transportation, and the sales & use tax bill.
    - Achievable Dream, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - American Jewish Committee, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Arab American Democrats of Virginia, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Asian Americans, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Board of Education, 2001 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Capital Projects (S.B. 673), 2002 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Constituents, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Dept. of Medical Assistant Services (DMAS), 2002 (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - Disabled Action Coalition (DAC), 2002 (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - Drivers License Bills (S.B. 612 & H.B. 638), 2002 (Box 74, Folder 11)
    - Economic & Fiscal Roundtable, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 12)
    - Education
      - Advancement Via Individual Determination Program, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 13)
      - Blueprint for Virginia Public Schools, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 14)
      - Brown v. Board of Education Scholarship Education Program, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 15)
      - Constitutional Change, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 16)
      - Dept. of Correctional Education, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 17)
      - Determining an Adequate Level of Public Support for Public Education, undated (Box 74, Folder 18)
      - ED Review, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 19)
      - Fairfax County Federation of Teachers Briefing, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 20)
      - Fall Election Effects & Beyond, undated (Box 74, Folder 21)
      - Georgia's HOPE Scholarship Program, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 22)
      - Governor's Education Initiative, 2003 (Box 74, Folder 23)
      - Higher Education Bond, undated (Box 74, Folder 24)
      - "How Should Reading Be Taught?", undated (Box 74, Folder 25)
      - Individualized Education Plan Online, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 26)
      - Los Angeles Unified School District News Release, 2001 (Box 74, Folder 27)
      - Multiracial Society with Segregated Schools: Are We Losing the Dream?, 2003 (Box 74, Folder 28)
      - National Education Goals Panel (NEGP), 2002 (Box 74, Folder 29)
      - National Teacher Salaries, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 30)
      - Renew Virginia Schools, 2003 (Box 74, Folder 31)
      - Secretary of Education, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 32)
      - State Council of Higher Education for Virginia, 2004 (Box 74, Folder 33)
      - Tax Restructuring & Education Funding, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 34)